# LAUREN ROUTIER | Back-End Developer, Full-Stack Developer

I am a people focused software engineer with a background in leadership and customer service. My experience in client facing roles gives me a clear vision of the end user experience and I utilize that perspective in my development projects.

# Skills

JavaScript, Vanilla Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Semantic, Canvas, Express, Liquid, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python, PostgreSQL, Django, Git, GitHub, Flv.io, Postman

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

**BAM POW** - DR application that allows users to add comics to a growing database and get suggestions based on their favorite comics

- Managed project Github for four person development team and resolved all merge conflicts in a timely manner
- Conducted daily stand-up meetings to get updates on each team member's progress and go over project goals for the day
- Utilized Diango, PostgreSql, React, and Axios along with Semantic UI for front-end styling

# **HONEY BADGES** - MERN stack social application that allows users to track and share activities

- Collaborated with a team of three other developers to build a full-stack application with full CRUD operations hitting all RESTFUL API calls
- Created custom badges and avatars for use in the app
- Back End Lead Developer, assisted on the Front-End by leveraging third-party API calls to allow users to generate a random activity

# **READING RAINBOW** - Full stack application the tracks client's reading goals and habits

- Made RESTful API calls to an Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman
- Styled and created the visual aspects using Liquid, Bootstrap, and CSS3
- Deployed using MongoDB Atlas and Fly.io

# THE MOTHMAN - Horror themed clue collecting game

- Utilized CSS as a key part of game functionality
- Leveraged Javascript methods, HTML5 and Canvas to manipulate the DOM

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **OrthoAtlanta**- Appointment Scheduler

Oct 2015 - May 2016

- Completed data entry for around 30 patients a day
- Created a positive and encouraging patient experience from the very first point of contact
- Trained fellow schedulers on new scheduling software

## TJ Maxx - Customer Experience Coordinator

November 2014 - Oct 2015

- Resolved customer complaints and issues in a prompt and courteous manner
- Supervised twice daily cash cash counts on all registers and transported large bills to main store safe
- Provided and accepted ongoing recognition and constructive feedback resulting in a stronger sense of teamwork within the sales team

#### **Verizon (WG Wireless)** - Store Manager

July 2014 - October 2014

- Spearheaded implementation of new organizational system to more efficiently keep track of customer information and past sales
- Managed store finances including both everyday cash flow up to \$5000 a day and the invoicing of high profile business customers for up to \$9000 per invoice
- Created and implemented tracking system for both individual and store sales goals for all 14 store branches earning individual recognition from the district manager and store recognition for achieving the highest sales for two months in a row

#### **EDUCATION**

## **General Assembly | 2022**